Guide to the James W. Robb papers, 1938-2000 MS0849.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
James W. Robb papers
1938-2000
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Robb, James W. (James Willis)
MS0849.UA
3 Linear Feet
Materials in this collection include Dr. James Robb's papers, correspondence, articles, framed photographs, LP Albums and books he had written on Alfonso Reyes. The material dates from 1938-2000.
Box UP0001
Box 1
Box 2
Acquisition Information
Collection was donated to University Archives by Dr. Robb.
Historical or Biographical Note
Dr. Robb is an Emeritus Professor of Romance Languages at The George Washington University. The collection covers the years 1938-2000.
Scope and Contents
Materials in this collection include Dr. James Robb's papers, correspondence, articles, framed photographs, LP Albums and books he had written on Alfonso Reyes. The material dates from 1938-2000.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Washington (D.C.); Photographs; George Washington University; Reyes, Alfonso; Robb, James W. (James Willis)
- Alfonso Reyes, Centennial, Madrid, 10/1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Alfonso Reyes, Centennial, Monterrey, Mexico City, 05/1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Alfonso Reyes, Comic book, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Alfonso Reyes, Celebratory Events, Spain, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Alfonso Reyes, Memorabilia- Mexico, Monterrey, 1959-1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Alfonso Reyes and Manuela M. De Reyes, 1955-1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Alfonso Reyes, Photographs and correspondence, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Alicia Reyes- Granddaughter of Alfonso Reyes, correspondence, 1966-1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Article on Alfonso Reyes by James Robb, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Article on Alfonso Reyes by James Robb, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Article on Martin Luis Guzman by James Robb, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Article: 'Neuva Novellistica' and card from Fernando Gonzalez (Spring), 1989 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Autographed correspondence of Latin American Writers, etc., 1953-1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Biographical information of James Robb, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Boletin Capilla Alfonsina (30, 33), 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Caminos Cruzados, Manvel Toussaint, Alfonso Reyes (Mexico En El Arte), 1983 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Columbianistas, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, Alfonso Rangel Guerra and James Robb, 1988-1996 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, Alicia Reyes and Dr. Alfonso, 1965-1997 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, Fernando Gonzalez and Thornton Wilder, 1941-1988 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Correspondence, German Archiniegas and James Robb, 1966-1989 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Correspondence, J.W.Robb and Alfonso Reyes, 1955-1964 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- France and French Writers, 1938-1969 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- German Gabriela Archiniegas, 1964-1988 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Homero Aridjis, 1966-1971 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Literary Congresses Conference, Symposia [1/2], 1961-1988 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Literary Congresses, Conference, Symposia [2/2], 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Magazines with Articles about Alfonso Reyes, 1961-1980 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Miscellaneous Articles, Correspondences, etc., 1966-1999 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Miscellaneous Articles, Correspondences, etc., 1966-1999 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Miscellaneous Articles, Correspondences, etc., 1966-1999 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Miscellaneous Alfonso Reyes Texts, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Monterrey, 05/1997 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Spanish School of Middlebury, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Various Correspondence to/from James Robb, 1949-2000 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Various Correspondence and Centenario Reyes Celebrations, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Scrapbook - Alfonso Reyes, Celebration Album, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
- La Capilla Alfonsina, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Diploma al Merito, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- LP album - Catalina Levirton, Recital Poetico, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- LP album - Lament on the Death of a Bullfighter, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- LP album - El Contemplado, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
- LP album and booklet - Archivo Dela Palabra, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- LP album and booklet - Alfonso Reyes, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 7)